MATTHEW WIDDOP

mrw078@student.bham.ac.uk \diamond MattyTheHacker.github.io Birmingham, UK \diamond linkedin.com/in/matthew-widdop REDACTED \diamond github.com/MattyTheHacker

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am currently studying a bachelor's degree in Computer Science at the University of Birmingham, currently averaging a first. I am primarily interested in software development, cyber security and networking. I have a clear record showing dedication to improving the student experience throughout the university and making positive change to benefit students and staff alike. My current primary project is the CSS website found at cssbham.com

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham, Birmingham

September 2021 - Present

B.Sc. Computer Science

- Object Oriented Programming (96%)
- Full Stack Application Development (100%)

University of Birmingham, Birmingham

September 2020 - July 2021

B.Sc. Engineering & Physical Sciences Foundation Year

- Elementary Computer Programming (99%)

Craven College, Skipton

September 2018 - July 2020

Level 3 Extended Diploma in Information Technology (D*D*D*)

South Craven Secondary School, Cross Hills

September 2013 - July 2018

13 GCSEs Grade 9 to 5(A* to C)

EXPERIENCE

School of Computer Science

September 2022 - Present

Student Ambassador

Birmingham, UK

· Provided information and tours to prospective students at open days and offer holder visit days.

Guild of Students, UoB

September 2022 - Present

Student Groups Assistant

Birmingham, UK

· Administrative and customer service duties for student societies at UoB.

MarketicUK

May 2019 - September 2022

Accountant

Leeds, UK

· All financial management, reporting and filing for the company.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS & SKILLS

Programming Languages Java, Python, Haskell, C

Markup Languages LaTeX, HTML, CSS, Markdown, PHP, JS, SQL, XML, JSON

Protocols & APIs REST, SSH, SFTP Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL

OSs Windows, Ubuntu, Kali, Tails

Tools Git, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, Excel, Google Sheets, Jupyter

CERTIFICATIONS, HONOURS AND AWARDS

Personal Skills Award (Advanced)

September 2022

· The Personal Skills Award (PSA) is the University of Birmingham's optional employability programme, designed to develop professional skills and attributes in preparation for graduate employment. Upon completion of the award, an assessment is undertaken which will demonstrate exceptional commitment to developing skills and fostering professional practice.

Bloomberg Market Concepts

August 2022

· Bloomberg Market Concepts (BMC) is a self-paced e-learning course that provides an interactive introduction to the financial markets. BMC consists of 3 sections — Core Concepts (includes four modules – Economic Indicators, Currencies, Fixed Income, Equities), Getting Started on the Terminal and Portfolio Management.

EXTRA CURRICULAR

UoB Sport and Fitness

October 2022 - Present

Club Development Executive - Combat Sports

Birmingham, UK

· Worked with the club development executive to represent the views of combat sports clubs.

Guild of Students Activities Committee

October 2022 - Present

Student Representative

Birmingham, UK

· Contributed to the strategic plan of the student groups department at the Guild.

University of Birmingham Senate

June 2022 - Present

UG Student Representative

Birmingham, UK

· Representing all 25,000 undergraduate students at UoB to the Senate.

College of Engineering and Physical Sciences, UoB

June 2022 - Present

College Representative

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for representing all 10,000 students within the college of EPS to the college level committees.

Misconduct and Academic Appeals Committee, UoB

May 2022 - Present

Nominated Student

Birmingham, UK

· Considered written and oral evidence as a full member of the committee to make decisions on student cases brought before the committee.

Jiu-Jitsu Club, UoB

March 2022 - Present

Captain

Birmingham, UK

· Responsible for the management and organisation of the Jiu Jitsu club at UoB with more than 55 members and 3 instructors.

Computer Science Society, UoB

February 2022 - Present

Industrial Liaison

Birmingham, UK

· Collaborated with industry contacts to secure sponsorship agreements for the society totaling around £5,000 so far, which is approximately 30% more than at this point last year.

School of Computer Science, UoB

October 2021 - Present

School Representative

Birmingham, UK

· Represtned the views and opinions of all 3,000 students in the SoCS to school level committees.